A Guide to the Phillips-Hargrove Family Papers, 1873-1945
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Phillips-Hargrove Family Papers, 1873-1945
The Library of Virginia
51611
.225 cubic feet (1 box and 1 folder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Judith A. Kane, Richmond.
Biographical Information
William Armistead Phillips (1835-1917) and Mary Willie Spears (1850-1907) were married in Richmond, Virginia on 29 April 1875. Their daughter Martha E. "Pattie" Phillips (1892-1962) married Nathan David Hargrove (1888-1962) on 10 December 1919. He attened Virginia Polytechnic Institute and the University of Virginia, and was a member of the Richmond Light Infantry Blues. Hargrove served in the infantry during World War I and was stationed at Camp Gordon in Augusta, Georgia. He attained the rank of second lieutenant. Following the war, he was employed by the Imperial Tobacco Company. He and his wife are both buried in Hollywood Cemetery in Richmond.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1873-1945, of the Phillips and Hargrove families of Henrico County and Richmond, Virginia, namely William Armistead Phillips (1835-1917) and his wife Mary Willie (Spears) Phillips (1850-1907), and their daughter Pattie P. (Phillips) Hargrove (1892-1962) and her husband Nathan David Hargrove (1888-1962). The collection includes deeds, insurance and loan papers, plats, title abstracts to property known as "Mount Erin," and information on its sale for a proposed enlargement of Powhatan Hill Park by the City of Richmond.
Contents List
- Clipping and Flyer - Park Opposition, 1915. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Deeds, 1873-1931. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Diplomas - John Marshall High School, 1909, 1910. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- "The First Adventurers to the Site of Richmond" by M. Ethel Kelly Kern. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Insurance, 1891. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter re: Trees, 20 December 1915. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Loan Extensions, 1934-1945. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Map of Land Proposed to be Acquired by City of Richmond for Municipal Purposed, 1930. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Map of Monument Avenue Gardens, 1923, 1924. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Map of William Christian's "Mount Erin" Estate. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Obituary of John Spears (1759-1842). (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ordinance - Powhatan Hill Park Enlargment, 1931. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Phillips Family Bible Record. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Promissory Notes, 1885. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Proposed Design for a City Park, 1915. (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- Receipts - Phillips v. City of Richmond, 1888. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Royal Arcanum Benefit Certificate, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Title Abstracts. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Title Insurance. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Will of Mary W. Phillips, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 15)